rankwatch.com 2019-06-08

# Terms and Conditions: RankWatch

### Terms of Use

The following terms and conditions govern all use of Web IQ technologies Pvt. Ltd offering Rankwatch website and all content, services and products available on or through the website. The website is owned and managed by Web IQ Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

**Description of Service**

RankWatch is a toolset for SEO professionals that provides Internet marketing tools for search engine optimization ("SEO") social media management (SMM) website optimization, including research and analysis, link building, campaign management, automated tracking of search engine performance, analytics and conversion tracking, and SEO reports.

**The "Service" includes**

(a) The Site,   
(b) The on-demand RankWatch SEO platform, tools and RankWatch API, and   
(c) The other services   

These services are provided to you through the site based on the plan purchased, including all software, data, text, images, sounds, videos, and other content made available through the site, or developed via the RankWatch API (collectively, "Content"). Any new features added to or augmenting the Service, are also subject to these Terms.

**Fee for Service**

RankWatch provides a free account and several tiered service, fee based accounts. Fees are based on the package the user has chosen. Each package has a base fee, which may incur extra charges for overages. Overage charges may apply to some services. You need to pay for services rendered above and beyond those included with your package.

**Account Downgrading**  
Downgrading your subscription plan level may cause the loss of content, features, or capacity of your account and you will be released by RankWatch from any liability for such loss. In order to initiate the account downgrading process, you must manually delete the number of keywords tracked to permit use of the service on the desired subscription plan tier. If you do not make those changes prior to requesting the downgrade of your account, the action will not be authorized and you will remain on your current subscription plan tier until all appropriate and requested actions are made.

**Representations and Warranties**  
You have to represent and warrant that all the information provided to RankWatch for using the service is correct, and current. Also, you need to ensure that you have all the necessary right, power, and authority to enter this agreement and perform the acts required as enumerated in this Agreement.

**Third-Party Content**  
Certain content, products or services made available through the RankWatch service may include materials from third parties. In addition, RankWatch may provide links to certain third-party websites as needed or to be used as reference when applicable. We are not responsible for this content or these websites, and you must agree not to hold us liable for any damage that may result from accessing or using them.

**No third Party Beneficiaries**  
As a user of the RankWatch service, you acknowledge that there shall be no third party beneficiaries to the agreement.

**Privacy**  
Your privacy is important to us and to ensure it, we have a transparent mechanism that details how we collect, use, and process your information. This Privacy Policy covers the information we collect about you when you use our products or when you interact with us (for example, via our support channels), unless a different policy is in place.  
As a condition of using the service, you must agree to the terms of the Privacy Policy. You must acknowledge, consent and agree that RankWatch may access, preserve and disclose your account information and any content or data, including the content of your e-mails if required to do so by law, or with a good faith belief that such access, preservation, or disclosure is desirable to comply with legal process, enforce our terms of service agreement, respond to claims that any content violates the rights of third parties, respond to your requests for customer service, or protect the rights, property or personal safety of RankWatch, its users, or any other party.

**Limitation of Liability**  
Under no circumstances shall RankWatch be liable to any user or third party on account of that user's use or misuse of or reliance on the service arising from any claim relating to this agreement or the website, or the service. Such limitation of liability shall apply to prevent recovery of direct, indirect, incidental, consequential, special, exemplary, and punitive damages including lost profits, lost sales or business, lost data or business interruption whether such claim is based on warranty, contract, or tort (including negligence). Without limiting the generality of the foregoing, under no circumstances shall RankWatch be held liable for any delay or failure in performance resulting directly or indirectly from acts, forces, or causes beyond its reasonable control, including, without limitation, Internet failures, computer equipment failures, telecommunication equipment failures, other equipment failures, electrical power failures, strikes, labor disputes (including lawful and unlawful strikes), riots, insurrections, civil disturbances shortages of labor or materials, fires, floods, storms, explosions, acts of God, war, governmental actions, orders of domestic or foreign courts or tribunals, non-performance of third parties, or loss of or fluctuations in heat, light, or air conditioning. RankWatch shall not be liable for any direct damages, costs, losses or liabilities whatsoever by any user or third party. Some states do not allow the exclusion of implied warranties or limitation of liability for incidental or consequential damages, which means that some of the above limitations may not apply to you. In these situations, ‘RankWatch' liability will be limited to the greatest extent permitted by law.

**Assignment**  
RankWatch may assign or transfer Agreement, in whole or in part, without restriction. In the event of an assignment or transfer, all rights to your data will be transferred, and you may be required by the beneficiary of the assignment or transfer to enter into a new agreement.

**Cancellation**  
You are responsible for properly cancelling your account. You may cancel your account at any time by going to your PayPal or Recur account to cancel future charges for the service. Any method of communication other than electing to cancel your subscription plan inside your selected payment method will not be considered cancelled. All of your content will be immediately deleted from the service upon cancellation. This data cannot be recovered once your account is cancelled. If you pay your subscription in monthly installments and you cancel your subscription prior to the end of the subscription period, RankWatch will terminate your access to the service and cease billing for future use of the service. However, you will remain responsible for all charges incurred prior to RankWatch terminating access to your account. Nonpayment of the RankWatch service seven (7) days after the last date of billing will constitute and initiate the cancellation of your account. After canceling your account by terminating future billings through PayPal or Recur, please submit a support ticket to initiate the termination of your account immediately.

**MODIFICATIONS**  
The RankWatch Team reserves the right, at its sole discretion, to modify or replace any part of these terms. It is your responsibility to check these Terms of Service periodically for changes. Your continued use of RankWatch service or access to RankWatch website following the changes in these Terms constitutes acceptance of those changes.

**Governing Law**  
This Agreement shall be governed by and construed under the laws of the state of India without reference to its conflict of law principles. In the event of any conflicts between foreign law, rules, and regulations, and Indian law, rules, and regulations, Indian law, rules, and regulations shall prevail and govern. Each party agrees to submit to the exclusive and personal jurisdiction of the courts located in New Delhi, India. The United Nations Convention on Contracts for the International Sale of Goods and the Uniform Computer Information Transactions Act shall not apply to this Agreement.

**RankWatch Fair Usage Policy**

RankWatch Fair Use Policy (FUP) applies to the use of the product, service or data, whether provided directly or by another party to provide it to Customer RankWatch Fair Usage Policy is intended to ensure:

  * That the product services are not used in an unreasonable manner.
  * The data fed for rank calculation is done in a systematic and ethical manner.
  * The data fed for rank calculation can be done upto 400% of the assigned keywords limit within a month.
  * Exceeding the above limit, RankWatch holds the right to freeze any additional changes on rank calculation data.
  * That use of the product services for any other purpose other than the intended usage is prohibited.
  * That the intention of tracking and processing the data other than to emulate human way of accessing may be prohibited.
  * By using the Software Services, Customer agrees to the Fair Usage Policy.

**'AppSumo Plan' Inactivity Clause.**

Appsumo Plan Inactivity Clause applies to all the customers that has signed up to RankWatch software services on the plans provided over Appsumo.com services. This clause includes the following:

  * If the above stated user has not logged in to its respective RankWatch software services account for 30 days period, RankWatch hold the right to temporarily pause any “data calculation” over the stated account.
  * The data calculation over the stated account would resume when the customer would log in to the its respective RankWatch software services account.

RankWatch holds the right to update the fair usage policy check detection mechanism on its discretion. If you wish to know more about how a specific condition affects you, please contact support.

### Privacy Policy

The Policy adheres strictly to the necessity to meet the new requirements for data processing as set out in the EU regulations governing personal data protection, namely the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 - GDPR (hereinafter: Regulation).  
We collect certain information relating to users who visit the site. RankWatch does not make any attempt to obtain information that personally identifies our users who visit our site. It is not our policy to sell or otherwise provide access to such information to unaffiliated third parties. We collect the e-mail addresses of those who communicate with us via e-mail, aggregate information on what pages consumer access or visit, and information volunteered by the consumer (such as survey information and/or site registrations). The information we collect is used to improve the content of our Web pages and the quality of our service, and is not shared with or sold to other organizations for commercial purposes, except to provide products or services you’ve requested, when we have your permission.

**Information Gathering and Usage**

We may collect personal information from Users in a variety of ways, including, but not limited to, when Users visit our site, fill out a form, and in connection with other activities, services, features or resources that we make available on our Site. Users may be asked to input their name, email address, phone number, address, payment information, and other information that we may deem desirable to collect for the purposes of delivering or enhancing our Site or services. Users may, however, visit our Site without providing this information. We will collect personal information from Users only if they voluntarily submit such information to us. Users can always refuse to supply personal information, except that it may prevent them from engaging in certain Site-related activities, and they will be unable to enroll in the service that we provide.

We may use the information we collect for internal reporting services, to create reports about rankings with all identifying information and keywords removed, and to help us help you. Namely, our service is designed to help you understand where you stand with your marketing efforts and to help us know how we can better serve you. Thus, we aggregate certain personal and non personal identifiable information, in an anonymous form, to help us develop new products, services, enhance existing ones, and create reports. We may collect non-personal information about users whenever they interact with our Site. Non-personal information may include the browser name, the type of computer, IP address, operating system, Internet Service Provider, and other technical information about users' means of visiting our Site.

**Your Rights**  
If you are located in countries that fall under the scope of the European General Data Protection Regulation, data protection laws give you rights with respect to your personal data, subject to any exemptions laid down by the law, including the rights to  

  * Request access to your personal data

  * Request correction or deletion of your personal data

  * Object to our use and processing of your personal data

  * Request that we limit our use and processing of your personal data

  * Request portability of your personal data.

You can usually access, correct, or delete your personal data using your account settings and tools that we offer, but in case you aren't able to do the same, you can drop us a message. Scroll down to find the option: How to Reach Us. EU individuals also have the right to make a complaint to a government supervisory authority.

**Web Browser Cookies**

Our Site may use "cookies" to enhance Users' experiences. Users' web browsers place cookies on their hard drives in order to allow us to distinguish user accounts for security and privacy reasons, and to conduct marketing campaigns, that we think may grab the attention of certain Users. For these reasons, enabling cookies is mandatory for full functionality of our Site and service.

**Data Ownership**

RankWatch uses third party vendors and hosting partners to provide the necessary hardware, software, networking, storage, and related technology required to run RankWatch. All search engine data and other important information collected through RankWatch is owned by RankWatch and licensed to its customers on an as-needed basis.

**How We Protect Your Information**

We adopt appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information, username, password, transaction information and data stored on our Site.

**Sharing Your Personal Information**

We do not sell, trade, or rent Users' personal information to others. We may share generic aggregated demographic information not linked to any personal information regarding visitors and users with our business partners, trusted affiliates and advertisers for the purposes outlined above and for any other purpose we deem desirable for our business operations or our Users.

**Changes To This Privacy Policy**

RankWatch has the discretion to update their privacy policy at any time. When we do, we will revise the updated date at the bottom of this page. We encourage Users to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this privacy policy each time you visit our website or use our service, and remain aware of any amendments.

**Your Acceptance Of These Terms**

By using this Site, you signify your acceptance of this policy and terms of service. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our Site. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of changes to this policy means that you accept those changes.
